Guide to the Archives of Irish America Vertical File Collection AIA.013
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Archives of Irish America Vertical Files
1866-2009 (Bulk 1970-2009)
AIA.013
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
22.0 linear feet (26 boxes)
The vertical files collection was created via active collection by staff, contributions from donors and from material removed from collections in the Archives. Materials collected on individuals, organizations and topics are included in the collection.
Archives of Irish America.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Vertical Files collection compliments the collections in the Archives of Irish America in that it provides information on many topics and individuals not formally represented in the collections. The unique format of many of the materials - fliers, posters, pamphlets - provide insight to scholars and researchers in the methods used to convey information within the Irish-American community.
Provenance
The vertical files collection was created via active collection by staff, contributions from donors and from material removed from collections in the Archives.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Arrangement
The collection is organized alphabetically. Oversize materials are organized alphabetically in separate series at the end of the collection.
Scope and Contents note
The Vertical File collection is an artificial collection of materials on various topics, individuals, and organizations both Irish-American and Irish with an emphasis on the latter. The collection includes contracts, constitutions, flyers, broadsides, leaflets, clippings, reports, pamphlets, catalogs, brochures, bibliographies, press releases, programs, sheet music and other printed ephemera, and is arranged alphabetically.
The bulk of this collection represents the type of literature commonly circulating within the New York Irish community since 1970. Information on more than 100 non-profit Irish American political and cultural organizations and events, businesses, the Irish language, one-time events such as demonstrations and poetry readings, and individuals is included. Also included are clippings and articles on famous Irish-Americans, gift catalogs, and information relating to publications. Some of the more documented institutions and topics covered are the Catholic Diocese, the Emerald Isle Immigration Center, the Glucksman Ireland House, the Irish American Cultural Institute, Irish Books and Media, Inc., The Irish Repertory Theatre, Saint Patrick's Day Parade organizations and events, and theater productions on and off Broadway. The majority of materials date from the 1970s and on.
American Conference for Irish Studies. American Committee for Irish Studies.; American Ireland Fund, The.; American-Irish Historical Society.; Boston College.; Catholic Church--United States.; Claidheamh Soluis (New York, N.Y.).; Clan-na-Gael.; Columbia University.; De Valera, Eamon, 1882-1975; Emerald Isle Immigration Center.; Flannery, Michael, 1902-1994.; Friendly Sons of St. Patrick.; Glucksman Ireland House. New York University.; Irish American Building Society.; Irish American Cultural Institute.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963; Knights of Columbus.; O'Hara, Maureen, 1920-; O'Neill, Tip; U2 (Musical group) .; Fliers (printed matter); Hunger strikes |z Northern Ireland.; Immigrants |z United States; Immigrants |z United States |x History |y 20th century.; Immigrants |z United States |x Political activity |x History |y 20th century.; Ireland |x History |y Easter Rising, 1916; Irish Americans; Irish Americans |x Music.; Irish Americans |x Politics and government; Irish Americans |x Social life and customs.; Irish Americans |x Societies, etc.; Irish Americans |z New York (State) |z New York |x Social life and customs.; Labor unions.; Pamphlets.; Playbills.; Political prisoners |z Ireland.; Publications.; Publishers and publishing |z United States.; Saint Patrick's Day.; Theater programs.; Theatre.
- A
  - Abu-Jamal, Mumia, 2000; 1 folder (Box 1)
  - The Adrian Flannelly Show, 1993-; 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Aer Lingus, 1979-; 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Aireagal, 2002-2004; 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Aisling Irish Community Center, 2005-2006; 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Allied Irish Banks, 1975-1998; 1 folder (Box 1)
  - American Bicentennial, 1974-1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
  - The American Civil War and the Irish, 1998; 1 folder (Box 1)
  - American Commission on Irish Independence, undated (Box 1)
  - The American Committee for Relief in Ireland (An Cumann Cabhrach), May 1921; 1 folder (Box 1)
  - American Committee for Sean O'Casey's Centenary, 1979 (Box 1)
  - American Conference for Irish Studies, 1963-2008; 4 Folders (Box 1)
  - American Foundation for Irish Heritage, 1990-1993; 1 folder (Box 1)
  - American Friends of James Joyce, 1998; 1 folder (Box 1)
  - The American Ireland Fund: Connections, 1994-2001; 3 Folders (Box 1)
  - The American Ireland Fund: Dinner Dances, 1995-2002; 2 Folders (Box 1)
  - American Irish Association Handbook, 1940s; 1 folder (Box 1)
  - American-Irish Association of Westchester County, 1977, 1986-1988, 1994; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - American Irish Celtic USA Stamp Committee, 1998-1999; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - American Irish Cultural Project, 1979; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - American Irish Defense Association, circa 1942; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - American Irish Foundation, 1976; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - American-Irish Historical Society, 1981-2006; 3 Folders (Box 2)
  - American Irish Immigration Center, 1968; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - American Irish Library, undated; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - American Irish Musicians Society, 1985; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - American Irish National Immigration Committee, 1969; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - The American Irish Newsletter, 1984, 1987; 1 regular folder, 1 oversize folder (Box 20)
  - The American Irish Society of Westchester County, Oct 1992; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - American Irish Teachers Association, Inc., 1986-2009; 2 Folders (Box 2)
  - American Irish Unity Committee, Jul 1981; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - American League for an Undivided Ireland, undated; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, 2006; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - An Club Leabhar, 1996-1997; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - An Comunn Gaidhealach Ameireaga, 1996; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - An Féinics, 1969; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - An Gorta Mór, 2000-; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - An Scáthán (The Celtic Mirror), 1997; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - An Scoil Ghaeilge (The Irish School), circa 1980-1996; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - An Scoil Nua, 1993-1996; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - An Teanga Mharthanach, 1990-1996; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Anamchairde Network, Inc., 1995-1999; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Ancient Order of Hibernians, 1974, 2000; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Anti-Apartheid Movement, circa 1990; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Archives of Irish America, 2001; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Art Exhibitions, 1973-2008; 2 folders, 1 oversize (Oversize 2, 22 (OV))
  - Art Auction Catalogs, 1999-2001; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Art From the Edge: New Irish Art, 1995-1996; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Artane Boys Band at Gaelic Park, 1961; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Ashe, Thomas, 2001 (Box 21)
  - Associated Irish Societies of New York, 1963, 1980; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Association to Promote Intercultural Relations, 1994; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Authors, 1997-1999; 1 folder (Box 2)
- B
  - Bailis, Moira, 1990-1995; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Bank of Ireland, 1987-1993; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Behan, Mae, 1994; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Benefit Dances, 1993, 2004; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Bergen Irish Association, 1989; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - The Bernard Shaw Society, 1986, 1994-1999; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Bewley's of Ireland, 1994-2000; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Bibliographies (includes bibliography on Irish Women), 1995, undated; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - The Many Stories of Billy the Kid, 1999; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Blarney Woolen Mills Gift Catalogue, 1997-2002; 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Bloomsday: Celebration of James Joyce, 1991-2004; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Bonded Shores, 1997-2000; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Former Title
    Bonded Shores was formerly called the Carolina Irish
  - Book Announcement from U.S. Publishers, 1998-; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Book Events, 1965-2001, undated; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Book Reviews, 1989-2001, undated; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Book Sellers, 1977-; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Books Written in Irish, 1998; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Boston College, 1993-2003; 2 Folders (Box 3)
  - Boston College Gaelic Roots Festival, 1997; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Boston College: Irish Film Series, undated; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Boston Irish Tourism Association, undated; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Brehon Law Society, 1994; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Breslin, Jimmy, 1986; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Broadway [Theater for Broadway, Off-Broadway, and Off-Off-Broadway Productions]
  - Brooklyn Academy of Music, May 1937; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Brooklyn Public Library: Irish Language Classes, circa 1996; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Buckley, Charles A. (politician), undated (Box 20)
  - Bucks County Irish Center, 1995; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Bulger, James "Whitey", 2001; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Burke, Michael, 1987; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Business Cards, undated; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Business Directories, 1991-2000; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Businesses Based in Ireland and England, 1994-1995; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Businesses Based in NYC, 1995-; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Businesses Based in the U.S., 1990-; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Butler, Father Francis, 1997-1998; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Byrne, John, 1978; 1 folder (Box 3)
- C
  - Caldwell, Marc, 1999; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Campbell, Father Colm, 2000; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Carmelite Parishes, 1988-1989; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Carmelites: Centennial, 1989; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Cashs of Ireland, 1997-2002; 2 Folders (Box 3)
  - Catholic Churches and Events, 1945-; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Catholic Diocese, 1.0 linear feet 14 Folders (Box 4)
    - Columban Fathers, 1971-1976; 2 Folders, 1 oversize folder (Box 4)
    - Irish Franciscan Brothers, 1968-1986; 8 Folders (Box 4)
    - Mill Hill Fathers, 1984-1988; 2 Folders (Box 4)
    - Knights of Columbus, 1983-1996; 2 Folders (Box 4)
  - Catholic Schools, 1948-; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Catholic University of America: Irish Studies, 1993-1998; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Catskills Irish Arts Week, 1994-2000; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Cee Vee Productions, 1998-; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Celebrating 250 Years of the New York City Saint Patrick's Day Parade. John Ridge and Lynn Mosher Bushnell. Quinnipiac University Press. 2010. Publicity and promotional materials. (Box 3)
  - Celtic League American Branch, 1974-1999, 2005; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Celtic Studies Association, 1992-1996; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Celtic Video/Celtic Productions, circa 1988-1995; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Ceol Na Ngael, 1991-; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Charities: Ethnic Appeals, 1991-2000; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Charities: Religious, circa 1989-1999; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Charity for Families and Individuals in Need, 1986-; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Chicago Irish American News, Dec 1979; 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Chicago Irish Folklife Society, 1987; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Church of Saint Francis Xavier, 1989; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - The Church of Saint James, 1995; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Church of Saint Teresa, 1996; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Cineaste, 1999; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Citizenship and Nationalism (Irish), 1971, 1996, undated; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - The City Center, circa 1950; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - City University of New York, 1993-2002; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Civil War Soldiers, 1992; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Clan Associations and Societies in the U.S., 1992; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Clan Na Gael, 1983-2000; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Collins, Ray, circa 1986; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Columbia University: Irish Studies, 1970-2000; 2 Folders (Box 5)
  - Comhairle Na Gcumann Gaeilge, Apr 1967; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Comhaltas Ceoltoiri Eireann, 1973-1999; 2 Folders (Box 5)
  - Commodore Barry Club of Brooklyn, 1976; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Concerts, 1945-; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Conferences, 2005 (Box 22)
  - Connecticut Irish-American Historical Society, 1990-2001; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Connor, Jerome (1874-1943): Irish-American sculptor, 1993; 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Conradh Na Gaeilge: New York, 1998; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Conradh Na Gaeilge: Texas, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Conradh Na Gaeilge: Washington, 1990-1999; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Conradh Na Gaeilge: Wisconsin, 1995-; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Constitution of Ireland, 1980; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Consulate General of Ireland in New York, 1999-2003; 1 folder (Box 5, Box 22)
  - Consultants, 1996-; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Conway, Michael- "Justice for Michael Conway" Issued by the Conway Defence Picket Line Committee), 1936 (Box 5)
  - Cooke, Terence J., 1968, 1981, 1983; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Cooking, 1987-; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Co-Operation Ireland, 1992; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Cork University Press, 1997-2001; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Creative Irish Gifts (3 folders), 1997-2005; 3 Folders (Box 20)
  - Crests and Coat of Arms; Family Names, 1901-1962 (Box 5)
  - Croí West of Ireland Cardiology Foundation, 2000; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Bing Crosby Sheet Music, 1944, 1947; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Cruises: Irish-Themed, 1992-; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Cudahy, Dorothy Hayden, 1951-; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Cuite, Thomas J., 2000 (Box 20)
  - Cultural Arts, 1997-2000; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Cumann Breandain, 1992-1997; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Cumann Na Gaeilge, 1999; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Curley, James Michael, 1992; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Curran, Sean, 1999-2000; 1 folder (Box 6)
- D
  - Daltaí Na Gaeilge, 2003-; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Daltai Na Gaeilge, 1993-; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Dance, 1969-2000; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Dance Study Programs, 1999, undated; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Dancing on Dangerous Ground, Mar 2000; 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Dara Records Irish Music News and Catalog, 1998-; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - De Valera, Eamonn, 1945-; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Doherty, Joe, circa 1984 (Box 6)
  - The Douglas Hyde Foundation for Irish-Medium Education, 1991-1994; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Clare Droesch, 2000; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Dufour Editions, Inc., 1994-1997; 3 Folders (Box 6)
  - Durkan, Frank, 2000-2006; 1 folder (Box 6, 22)
- E
  - Eagle Tavern and the Blarney Star, 1991-2001; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Easter Uprising Commemoration, 1969-1995 (Box 20)
  - Easter Uprising of 1916, 1961-1997; 2 Folders (Box 6)
  - Echoes of Irish History, by Mike McCormack, undated; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Economy of Ireland, 2000; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Eire Ireland - various articles - John F. Kennedy, 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Éire Philatelic Association, 1977; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Eire Society of Boston, 1960-1974; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Ellis Island, undated; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Ellis Island: Dedication of Annie Moore Statue, May 1993; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Emerald Association of Long Island, Inc., 1969-1978; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Emerald Isle Festival, 1992-1993; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Emerald Isle Immigration Center, 1989-2008; 7 Folders (Box 6, 7, 20)
  - Emerald Platinum Plus, circa 1998-1999; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - The Emmet Club, undated; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Event Ads and Press Releases in Ireland, 1994-; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Event Ads and Press Releases in NYC, 1988-; 2 Folders (Box 7)
  - Event Ads and Press Releases in U.S./Outside NYC, 1986-; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Exhibits: "The Fifth Province", 2010 (Box 7)
- F
  - Fairfield University: Irish Studies, 2000; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Family History Research Aids, 1991-; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - The Family Tree International Newsletter, 1994-1997; 1folder (Box 7)
  - Famine: Canada - Grosse Íle, 1992-; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Famine/Genocide Remembrances (U.S.), 1994-; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Farrell, Patric, c. 1915, 2008 (Box 21)
  - Festivals: New York City and New York State, 1869, 1986, undated; 1 folder, 1 oversize folder (Box 7)
  - Festivals: United States (outside NYC and Washington D.C.), 1973-; 1 folder, 1 oversize folder (Box 7)
  - Festivals: Washington D.C., 1996-; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Film Events: NYC, 1988-; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Film Events: Outside NYC, 1992-; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Film Fleadh Foundation, 1998-; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Film: On Irish and Irish America, 1940-1996; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Film: On Irish and Irish America, circa 1997-; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Film: On Northern Ireland, 1990-1997, undated; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Film Reviews, 1992-; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - The Film Society of Lincoln Center/Glucksman Ireland House, 1993; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Fitt, Jerry, Mar 1968; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Fitzpatrick Manhattan Hotel, 1992-1993; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Fitzpatrick, Thomas, undated; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Flannery, Michael, 1983, 1992; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Flannery, Michael: Long Kesh Hunger Strike Commemoration, 2001; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Florida Irish Festivals, undated; 1 folder (Box 21)
  - Flynn, Raymond L. (Mayor of Boston, Ambassord to the Vatican), undated; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Foley, Thomas (Speaker, U.S. House of Representatives), 1989; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Food and Beverage Importers, 1992-1999; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Fordham University: Institute of Irish Studies, 1978-1979, 1998-2002; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Four Courts Press Dublin, 1997-2001; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Frances Pope Memorial Foundation, 1984-1989; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Frances Schervier Home and Hospital, 1988; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Society of the Friendly Sons of St. Patrick (Long Island): Annual Luncheon, Dec 1986; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Society of the Friendly Sons of St. Patrick in New York City: Charter, Constitution, By-Laws, etc., 1922; 3 Folders (Box 8)
  - Society of the Friendly Sons of St. Patrick in New York City: Anniversary Dinner Seating lists, 1966-1967, 1974, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Society of the Friendly Sons of St. Patrick in New York City: Anniversary Dinner Programs (with gaps), 1966-1989 (Box 8)
  - Society of the Friendly Sons of St. Patrick in New York City, 1975-1997 (Box 8)
  - Society of the Friendly Sons of St. Patrick in New York City: Yearbooks, 1995-1996 (Box 8)
  - Friends of Fianna Fáil, 1988; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Friends of Irish Freedom, May 1994; 1 folder (Box 8)
- G
  - Gaelic Park, 2001; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - The Gaelic Society (NYC), 1969; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Gaffney, Nan Fitzpatrick, 1997-; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Gallagher, Father Michael J., 1996; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Gallagher, Miriam, 1992; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Gallon, Dale, undated; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Galway Show, 2002; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Garden State Annual Irish Festival, 1992-; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Gay, Dorothy Kelly (Mayor of Somerville, MA), 2001; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Genealogy, undated; 1 folder, 1 oversize folder (Box 8)
  - Gift and Novelty Sellers (UK and Ireland), 1999-2001; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Gift and Novelty Sellers (U.S.) (4 folders), 1994-1996 (Box 8)
  - Gleason, Thomas, 1984-; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Global Exchange Reality Tours, 1998-; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Glucksman Ireland House (3 Folders), 1991-2003 (Box 9, Box 22)
  - The Good Shepherd: Silver Jubilee Dedication Book, 1937; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Graduate Irish Studies Conference, 1993-1994, 1999; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Gralton, Jimmy, 1945; 1 folder (Box 21)
  - The Great Hunger Memorial/Irish Hunger Memorial, 1994-; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - The Great Irish Fair, 1981-1998; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Greeley, Father Andrew, 1971-1976; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Green Linnet Irish Music Party, 1993-1996; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Green Linnet Records, 1993-1998; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Greeting Cards, circa 1993-; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - The Grian Association, 1999-2004; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Grimes Travel, 1991-1997; 1folder (Box 9)
  - A Guide to Irish Studies in the U.S., 1982, 1987, 1995; 1folder (Box 9)
  - Guinan, Matthew, 1995; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Guiness Fleadh, 1997; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Guiness Import Co., 2001; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Guinness Oyster Festival, 1997-1999; 1 folder (Box 9)
- H
  - Haas, Richard, 2001; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Haggerty, James, 1992; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Hammond, John Lawrence, 1921; 1 folder (Box 21)
  - The Harp and Shamrock Club, Inc., Aug 1956; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Harrison, George, 2000; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Haughey, Charles J., 2000; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Hibernian Benevolent Association of the City of Troy, 1841; 1 folder (Box 21)
  - Hughes, John D.D., 1866, undated; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Hume, John (Northern Ireland Map), 2005; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Hunter Celtic Club, 1973; 1 folder (Box 9)
- I
  - Images and Representations of Irish Americans, 1989-; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Immersion Weekends, 1995-; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Immigrants in U.S. ("New Irish"), 1980s-; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Immigration to North America, 1985-2006; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Immigration: Notes and Bills, 1975; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Immigration Reform, circa 2005; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Independent Irish Society Inc., Mar 1985; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Information Ireland, 1994; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Inside Ireland, 2003; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - International Gaelic Hall of Fame, 1972-1974; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - International Rebel Music Festival, 1986; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - International Socialism 51, 1972; 1 folder (Box 21)
  - Invitations, 1995, 2000; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Iona College Libraries: Bibliography of Gaelic Language Materials, 1998; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Ireland Chamber of Commerce USA, 1988-1994; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Ireland Digest, undated; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Ireland Diskovered, 1997; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - The Ireland Fund, undated; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Ireland International Institute, 1992; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Ireland on Parade, 1964; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1966, 1994; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Ireland's Children (NY), 1975-1979; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Irish Academic Press, 1997-2000; 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Irish Ad Hoc Society in Support of Jesse Jackson, circa 1988; 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Irish Advocate Magazine, 1992; 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Irish America Magazine, 1992-; 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Irish American Athletic Club, 1908-1915, 2010 (Box 10)
  - Irish American Book Company, 1997-1999; 2 Folders (Box 10)
  - Irish American Building Society, 1996-2003; 3 Folders (Box 10)
  - Irish American Center, 1982; 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Irish American Committee to Elect David Dinkins, 1989; 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Irish American Cultural Center of NY, 1985-1992; 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Irish-American Cultural Festival, 1997-1998; 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Irish American Cultural Institute, 1972-2002; 5 Folders (Box 10)
  - Irish American Cultural Organizations, 1981-; 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Irish American Fenian Society, Inc., 1986, 1992; 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Irish American Film Foundation, circa 1998-1999; 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Irish American Heritage Center, 1994; 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Irish-American Heritage and Culture Week Committee, Inc., 1985-1995; 2 Folders (Box 10)
  - Irish-American Heritage Month Events, 1991-1995, 2000; 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Irish American Heritage Museum, 1988-; 1 folder (Box 11)
  - The Irish American Hour, 1983; 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Irish American Labor Coalition, 1986, 1994; 1 folder (Box 11)
  - The Irish-American Link, Mar 1976; 1 folder (Box 21)
  - Irish American Movement: The Irish Race Convention, 1994; 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Irish American Network Foundation, 1991; 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Irish American Partnership, 1993-; 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Irish-American Political Action Association, 1975; 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Irish American Press, undated; 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Irish American Public Action Committee, Inc., 1992-1996; 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Irish American Singles Association, undated; 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Irish American Singles Club of N.J., undated; 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Irish American Society of Greater Richmond, undated; 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Irish-American Society of Nassau, Suffolk and Queens, Inc., 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Irish American Teamsters, 1994; 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Irish American Unity Conference, 2000-; 1 folder (Box 11)